Guide to the Howard Gillette Papers, 1826-2018 MS0644.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- DC culture, government, suburbs, community life and city programs, 1845-2013; Series 2
  - Law Firms, 1981-1986; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - Latinos Civil Rights Task Force, 1991-1992; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - DC Literature, 1980-1985; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - The Mall, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - Malls, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - Memorial Bridge, 1974-1995; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - World War II Memorial, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - Murals, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - D.C. Music, 1985-1996; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - Names, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 93)
  - Washington DC Resources, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - DC Bibliographies, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - American Institute of Architects, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Catholic University, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - DC Archives, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Moorland - Spingarn Center, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - DC Maps, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - DC Contempt Stat, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Washington Area Tours, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Book Reviews/DC, 1985; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Don Hawkins TJ's sketches & the founding of the federal city, 1988; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Boyd, Papers Thomas Jefferson Vol. 20, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Chs 1 & 2 DC history, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Larson 'A bridge, A dam, A River: Liberty and Innovation in the Early Republic, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Guttheim, Washington on the 18th century, April 10, 1981; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Untitled [Jennings, Artistry as Design L'Enfant's Extraordinary City], 1979; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Scott "This Vast Empire", 1991; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Alexandria: Afro - Am Archeology, 1993; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Sweig, Donald 'A Capital on the Potomac' VA May of Hist & Biog 87, 1979; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Verheyer White House in the Federal City, 1981; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Verheyer...Reconstructing Jefferson in the Planning of Washington, 1978; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Martin Gordon The Military Impact on Federal Control, 1978; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Sorg, Suman 'Catalogue of Art of Arts from Bryant St. Pumping Station...DC', August 12, 1976; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Documenting the District's History, October 1984; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - "L'Enfant Terrible" Washington Magazine, January 1990; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Ms. Thornton's Arthur Soc. Sci. Hist Fall 91, 1991; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Horton Life and Times of Edward Ambush, 1984; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Dorothy Provine "Economic Position of Free Blacks in DC", January 1973; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Berlin Wartime Genesis of Free Labor- The Upper South DC, 1993; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Shephard, "Obtaining Water & Discarding Waste" Alexandria 19th cent, January 5, 1989; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Joseph Reidy 'Coming from the Shadow of the Past Transition from Slavery to Freedom at Freedmen's Village VA Mag of Hist & Blog 95, October 1987; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Horton and Horton Race, occupation & literacy in reconstruction, DC, 1982; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Maury, Alex. "Shepherd and the Board of public works, 1973; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Olmstead in DC, 1985; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Army core of engineers & Jr improvement of the Anacostia River, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Rock creek & recreation; Evelyn, May 7, 1987; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Porter, John Addison 'The City of Washington' 1805, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Jacob Old Elite withdraws into its shell, 1993; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Candice Sherman Rise of Christian Heurich and His mansion Washington History SP/Summer, 1993; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Lessoff 'Gilded Age Washington', 1992; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Henry Davis Political Development the D of C, 1988; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Harrison, Robert 'The Ideal of a Model City, 1905-09', August 1989; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Murphy Dept of Age, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Longstreath 'Early Commercial Washington', Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Orlin, Glenn Development in the Parking Concept, March 4, 1983; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Sarah Leach Fifty years of parkway construction in and Around the nation's capital, 1990; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Visual Journey: Harlem and DC, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Johnson Black writers of the 1920s CHS Records, 1980; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Lewis Afro Am Domestics, 1987; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Abbott, "Perspectives on Econ. Planning DC since 1880", 1989; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Longstreath 'The Neighborhood Shopping Center in Washington, 1930-41" JSAH, 1992; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Longstreath Hecht Co Branch development, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Polsby, "The Washington Community", 1981; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Wolters 'Washington Showcase of integration, 1984; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Marvin Caplan Eat Anywhere, 1999; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Henig and Gale 'Political Inc. of New Corners to Racially Changing Neighborhoods, UAQ, 1987; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Finkel "life and Death on Acker Street", May 8, 1994; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Gillette Miller "Race Relations in Washington DC, 1994-1995; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Abbott "Dimensions of Regional Change in Washington DC", Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Abbott, Carl. The Internationalization of Washington DC Urban Affairs review 31, May 1996; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Kozel, Savage Inequalities "The Equity of Innocence DC", 1992; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Charles Suddarth Kelly Washington, Then and Now, 1996; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Washington the Lost Colony, 1966; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Peg Henry An Evolution of Decentralization, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - George Grier Comings and Goings in the Washington Area, April 1994; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Henrickson, 'A small crazy town, global in scope', 1983; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Diner 'Crisis of confidence public confidence in the schools of nation's capital, 1990; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Henig 'Race and Voting Urban Affairs Quarterly, June 1993; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Hening Building Conditions for sustainable school reform in DC, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Bruce Adams, 'Building Healthy Communities, 1995; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Citizens Plan for Prosperity, November 1998; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Washington Descriptions, 1830; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - 1820 Laying of the corner stone for city hall DC, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Southard Report, 1835; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Rep Party - 19th century, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Black Slave, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Reconstruction, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Walter's letter 1861, June 8, 1992; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Women's suffrage DC, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Early suburban advertising, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Suburban, 19th century, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - Blacks 1880, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - Alley Reform, 1912-1914; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - City Planning Meeting, 1909; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 84)
  - NCPC, 1926; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 85)
  - World War II, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 86)
  - Post World War II, 1944; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 87)
  - Bureau of the Budget: Planning the National Capital, March 1944 (Box 6, Folder 88)
  - Covenants, 1948; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 89)
  - Schools, 1950; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 90)
  - Integration, 1950; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 91)
  - "Wicked" 2nd Precint, March 14, 1954; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 92)
  - NW #1 Redevelopment, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 93)
  - Riots & Aftermath, 1983; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 94)
  - Log, State of the Region, 1970; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 95)
  - Housing Policy for the DC govt, 1980; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 96)
  - Message from the President of the United States to the two houses of Congress at the Commencement of the second session of the thirty second congress, 1852 (Box 6, Folder 97)
  - 14th St., 1982-1992; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 16th St., 1978; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 17th St., 1988; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - F Street, Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - G Street, 1984; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - H Street, 1997; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - U Street, 1988-1999; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Columbia Road, 1998; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Connecticut Ave, 1995; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Georgia Ave, 1982-1998; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - New York Ave, 1992-1997; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Pennsylvania Ave, 1996; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Route 1, 1980; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - I-270, Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Streets, Misc., 1981-1984; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Downtown, 1964-1995; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Downtown: Franklin Square, 1988; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Adams-Morgan, 1968-1988; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - DC Anacostia, 1984-1986; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Brightwood, 1988-1996; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Brookland, 1980-1993; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Capital Hill, 1986; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Chinatown, Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Cleveland Park, Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Columbia Heights, 1998-1999; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Congress Heights, 1981-1989; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Crestwood, 1992; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Eckington, 1996; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Foggy Bottom, 1999; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Fort Lincoln, 1992; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Friendship Heights, 1984; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Georgetown, 1980-1996; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - LeDroit Park, 1998; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Lincoln Park, 1987-1997; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Logan Circle, 1996; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Marshall Heights, 1997-1998; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Mt. Pleasant, 1977-1993; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Mt Pleasant Bulletin Board, 1994-1995; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Historic Mt. Pleasant, 1992-1999; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Gale, "Back to the City Movement", Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Northeast, 1987-1992; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Palisades, 1978-1988; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Petworth, 1984; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Shaw, 1986-1996; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Shepard Park, 1987; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Southeast, 1984-1996; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - DC Sweat, 1997; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - SW: Our Square, 1939; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Spring Valley, 1986; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - D.C. Takoma Park, 1977-1995; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - West End, 1991; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Woodley Park, 1978; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - DC Suburbs, 1985-1996; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Norton VA, 1978-1993; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Tysons Corner, 1982-1999; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Alexandria, 1987-1996; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Arlington, 1992-1995; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Arlington: Ballston, 1995; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Bethesda, Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Arlington, Alexandria Records, Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Chevy Chase, 1987; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Fairfax, 1986-1990; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Fairfax County, Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Frederick, 1979; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Gaithersburg, 1986-1996; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Hyattsville, 1980-1986; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Laurel, 1997; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Montgomery County, 1991; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - DC: Prince Georges County, 1998-1999; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Rockville, 1995; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Silver Spring, 1999; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Vienna, 1983; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Wheaton, Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - Outer Suburbs, 1986-1989; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Anne Arundel County, 1979-1986; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Calvert County, 1983; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Loudon County, 1995; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Prince William County, 1997-1998; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Space and Culture in Washington, DC: A Capital in Search of a City, Undated; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - DC History, Culture, Politics, 1999; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - A Historical Bibliography of the Built Environment in the Washington, D.C., Metropolitan Area, 2001; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - DC Photo File, 1943-1990; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - DC Culture: Contemporary, 1988-2013; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - DC Documents, 1885-1978; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Ruskin, DC, and the Right to Vote (Winter), 1999; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - DC: Regional Paper, 1994-1998; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - DC Agenda, 1999-2001; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - DC Historical Society, 2010-2011; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - DC Control Board, 1980-1999; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Robert Manning: Ethnicity in DC, 1998; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - DC: Fiscal Crisis, 1994-1998; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - DC: Downtown, 1999-2004; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - DC: Highways, 1987-2000; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Home Rule Act, as amended, 1989; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Smith, Sam: Divided We Stand, 1987-1988; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - CQ Researcher: Governing DC, 1996; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Home Rule, 1949-2014; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Retrocession, 1981-1996; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - The Mall, 2002-2003; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - DC: Metro, 2001; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Obituaries, 1987-2002; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - DC: Planning, Contemporary, 1974-1998; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - DC: Race, 1937-2008; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - DC: Security, 2003-2006; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - DC: Statistics and Maps, 1969-2011; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - DC Suburbs, 1982-2002; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Compromise of 1790, Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Jennings, L'Enfant, 1979-1986; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Banner, "The Capital and the State", 1999; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - John Addison Porter, "The City of Washington", 1845-1924; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Franklin Webster Smith, Plan for DC, 1900; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - City Beautiful, 1900-2000; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Improvement of the City of Washington, 1901; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Weller, Neglected Neighbors, 1909-1910; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Imaging in the City in the Americas: Washington and Mexico City, 1910-1996; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - Woodrow Wilson and Federal Segregation, Undated; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - 1930s, 1997; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - DC: Public Housing, 1941-1949; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - DC: Urban Renewal, 1942-1999; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - Barnes, DC Housing and Redevelopment, 1977; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - Marion Barry, 1995-2014; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - Williams, Anthony, 1998-2003; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - Adjaye, David, 2013; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - Gutheim, Frederick A., 1947-1994; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 46)
  - Jones, Edward P., 2004-2007; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 47)
  - DC Social History, 1985-1995; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 48)
  - DC Photographs, Undated; Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 49)
- Correspondence, letters and notes, 1975-1995; Series 3
  This series contains Howard Gillette's correspondence, letters, memos, and notes. These materials cover a wide range of topics, including seminars, George Washington University courses, and Beauty and Justice—one of Gillette's books. The materials range in date from 1972 to 1995. More specifically, this series contains Gillette's memos from 1983 to 1993 and his correspondence from 1975 to 1995
  - ASA - 1995, Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - AHA, American Historical Association 1992, Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Planning History Conference, 1993-11; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - PSHP, Philadelphia Social History Project, 1975-1977; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Urban History Association Meeting, 1992; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Urban History Prize, 1992; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Urban Odyssey, 1988; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Urban Odyssey, 1991; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - HG Clips, Notices, 1972-1988; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Grant Applications - HG, 1982-1983; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - N.E.H Complete Submission, 1982-1983; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - N.E.H. Original Letter, 1993; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - N.E.H. Course Material, 1993; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - W. History Correspondence, 1990-1993; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Washington History - Current, 1993-1994; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Washington Works, 1982-1991; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - H. SW, Historical Society of Washington DC, 1993; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - DC Historical Studies, 1982-1986; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - L'Enfant Fundraising, 1982-1986; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Bicentennial Minutes, 1987-1991; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - School w/o Walls, 1992-1993; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Alexandria Consulting, 1994; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Memos, 1983-1984; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Memos, 1985-1986; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Memos, 1986-1987; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Memos, 1988-1989; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Memos, 1988-1989; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Memos, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Memos, 1991-1992; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Memos, 1992-1993; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1975-1976; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1977; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and Recommendation, 1976-1977; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence 1979-1980, Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1981; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1982; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1982-1983; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1984; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1985; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1986; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1987; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1988; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1989; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence 91-92, 1991-1992; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence 92-93, 1992-1993; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence 93-95, 1993-1994; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Publications Correspondence, 1972-1986; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Publication Correspondence, 1985-1993; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - HG Course List, 1971-1981; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - English Dept Courses Syllabi, 1986-1990; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1989-1990; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Ripon, 1977-19978; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - India, 1984; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Columbian College, 1983, Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Yale Reunion, Nov 94, 1994; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Encyclopedia of Washington, 1989-1991; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Unlabeled (Resumes), 1993; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Freelance Contributors, 1994; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - American Urbanism, 1987-1990; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Divided Metropolis, 1978-1982; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Editorial and Documental History, 1986-1988; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Ford Foundation: Women of Color Seminar, 1989; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Between Justice & Beauty Summer, 1995; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Washington Scene 1992 to Summer 1995, 1992-1995; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Octagon Book, 1995; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Octagon, 1993-1995; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - L'Enfant Papers, 1987-1989; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Alexandria Lyceum, 1982; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Decatur House, 1992; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Scholarly papers and publications, class materials and projects, 1826-2018; Series 4
  Boxes 12, 13, 14, and 17 follow the materials' original order. Boxes 18, 19, and 20 are arranged alphabetically.
  This series contains a variety of scholarly papers, publications, course materials, and projects. Materials include newspaper clippings, exhibition pamphlets, curricula, correspondence, notes, book excerpts, awards, and D.C. area organization's publications. The materials range in date from 1826 to 2008.
  - Associated Charities, 1998-2008; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Centennial, 1998-2008; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Documents: Foundations, 1826-1956; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Redevelopment, 1946-1985; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Canal, 1850-1855; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Parks, 1870-1893; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - RSR, 1883-1982; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Sewers, 1878-1932; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Schools, 1847-1858; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Street Rails, 1893-1984; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - City Beautiful, 1906-1955; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Civil War, 1863-1865; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - DC 1945-68, 1948-1965; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - DC Reconstruction, 1862- 1871; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Housing Reform 1940-1950's, 1919-1949; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - II Modernization, 1861-1902; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Social Reform, 1890-1922; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Post Civil War Development, 1867-1905; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Untitled, 1989; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Protest Clips and Notes, 1973-1992; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - City Beautiful Documents, 1893-1901; Series 4 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Association of American Geographers: Field Trip Guide, 1994; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Atlas of Maryland: A Commemorative Edition, 1977; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Children in Crisis: A Report on the Failure of DC's Public Schools, 1996; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - A Citizen's Guide to the Courts, 1989; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - City of the Constitution, 1987; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Comprehensive Plan for the National Capital, 1983; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Connecticut Avenue: P Street Project, 1977; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - DC Appleseed Center for Law and Justice, 1995-1996; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Department of Housing and Community Development, 1985; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Design Action, 1982; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Federal Capital Improvements Program for the National Capital Region, 1979-1984; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - The Future of the District of Columbia: Reunion with Maryland, 1996; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Greater Washington Research Center: Employment Opportunities in the Washington Metro Area for Persons with Limited Employment Qualifications, 1988; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Greater Washington Research Center: Employment and Training Activities Serving Predominantly Low-income Residents of Washington, DC, with Limited Employment Qualifications, 1988; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Greater Washington Research Center: The Financial Incentive Offered by Low-wage Jobs to Recipients of Income Support Benefits, 1988; Series 4 (Box 13, Folder 15)